Manuel Moran-Bojorquez

Project Manager

214-500-2524 | bestmetalbuildings@hotmail.com | 8104 Odell Street North Richland Hills, TX 76182

<u>Summary</u>

Experienced Project Manager with over 24 years of diverse construction experience, including project management and estimating. Experienced with both public and private sector projects ranging from: aviation, municipal, healthcare, hospitality, and resorts. Strong general management qualifications in market analysis, business planning, development functions, client relations, service, and leadership. Excellent analytical organization and negotiation skills. Ability to network with executive decision-makers and all levels of management make me a great asset.

Credentials

- OSHA 30 Training
- Microsoft Project Scheduling
- Primavera P6 Scheduling
- AutoCAD Experience
- Hard Bid Estimating
- Cost Works Estimating Software
- JOC Work Estimating
- E4 Clicks Estimating Software
- Experience with Commercial, Federal, Municipal, University, Healthcare, School Districts and Aviation Projects
- LEED Training
- Project Management Software
- Construction Quality Management with Corp. of Engineers
- Hard Bid Experience Quality Control Reading Plans and Specifications

Experience

<u>Project Manager/Estimator</u>, Exposed Floors Design Group, Dallas, TX (2017-2018)

- Provide and procure estimates for new and remediation construction projects.
- Thorough review of plans and specifications for estimates and clearly spells out scope of work.
- Oversee projects from procurement to final payout.
- Analyze project performance and budget through daily and weekly cost analysis sheets and production reports.
- Manage multiple projects at once while maintaining a high level of quality control.
- Attend pre-issuance site visits and meetings to determine existing conditions and develop client needs in detail

Project Manager, J.A. Watts, Inc., Dallas, TX (2016-2017)

- Managed American Airlines & US Airways Rebranding
- Part of the rebranding team focused on Latin American and the Caribbean which Includes 85 airports, 50 city ticket offices, and 6 reservation centers also, personally managing the rebranding of 34 sites throughout Mexico, Central America and the Caribbean.
- Prepare detailed proposals and estimates to the American Airlines CRE's Team.
- Develop detailed schedules.
 Manage delivery order execution by preparing Work Releases.
- Manage Subcontractors.
- Coordinate subcontractors and materials for multiple projects.
- Attend pre-issuance site visits and meetings to determine existing conditions and develop client needs in detail.

Project Manager / Sr. Estimator, Phillips May Corporation, Dallas, TX (2012-2016)

- Managed DFW Airport Job Order Contract.
- Worked on projects for American Airlines.
- Prepared detailed scopes of work for various projects and trades.
- Developed detailed schedules.
- Managed Superintendents and Assistant Project Managers.
- Coordinated subcontractors and materials for multiples projects.
- Attend pre-issuance site visits and meetings to determine existing conditions and develop client needs in detail.

Sr. Estimator / International Project Manager, Manhattan Construction, Dallas, TX (2009-2012)

- Responsible for gathering all data required in preparing lump sum, unit rate and cost plus detailed estimates.
- Responsible for conceptual estimating, cost analysis, and estimate coordination.
- Reviewed and develop discipline and multi-discipline takeoffs (MTO).
- Evaluated and/or developed construction labor rates and evaluated cost estimates and proposals.
- Performed productivity analysis of cost estimates, prepared contingency, escalation, and reconciliations for estimates.
- Performed comparisons of scope, quantities, and cost data between projects.
- Reviewed process designs and engineering specifications for cost effectiveness and suggested for alternates where applicable.
- Served as part of the Estimating, Pre-Construction and Project Engineering Group at the DFW International Airport TRIP's Project.

Sales Engineer / Project Manager, Star Buildings Systems, Oklahoma City, OK (1999-2009)

- Responsible for managing new business development and strategic planning to maximized growth and profitability. Established growth plans for individual accounts and managed accounts calls, presentation and negotiations.
- Researched and analyzed foreign markets. Identified potential markets and expanded sales regions.

• Established and maintained cooperative working relations with foreign companies because of providing superior service, extensive interaction and strong communication skills.

<u>Business Development Manager, Koch Industries</u> – Brazil, Argentina, Peru, Ecuador, Colombia, Venezuela (1991-1999)

• Sold and designed combustions equipment to gas power plants throughout Latin America. Involved in sales, design and customer service.

Education

- BS, Mechanical Engineering, Universidad de Costa Rica, Costa Rica. 1989
- BS, Structural Engineering, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK. 2003